♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you♪
♪Drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind♪
♪Let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
=The First Jasmine=
=Episode 16=
Above us all,
heaven exists.
May Grandmother rest in peace
and go to heaven.
(Ye Mansion)
Li! Wait a moment, Li.
You may get on the carriage first.
Just get to the point.
I want to know why you didn't expose me.
That's because you helped me too.
You helped me scare Father.
I helped you hide your secret.
We helped each other, so we're even.
Don't you hate me?
For what?
For trying to steal my dowry
and my mother's shop?
But I already took all of those back.
And I also made you lose face in public.
I married your father,
which caused your mother...
That matter has nothing to do with you.
Even without you back then,
they would still have driven my mom out.
If Father hadn't married you,
he would have married someone else.
If I should hate anyone,
it should be him, not you.
Ye Wenhua is heartless, faithless,
cowardly, and incompetent.
He is not a good man for any woman.
Marrying him might not
be a good thing for you.
How you live your life
is your own business.
I shouldn't interfere too much.
But Ye Rong is a good child.
Be a responsible mother.
And Ye Ying
needs your care as well.
I hope that before you act,
you remember to think more about them.
I will.
Thank you.
I'm leaving now. Take care.
Li.
Will you ever come back?
(Ye Mansion)
Li.
What are you doing?
I'm hungry.
You said you were hungry, right? Eat up.
You can actually cook?
It's just a simple meal.
If you're hungry, just let Ding cook.
No matter how late it is,
he can cook for you.
Stop eating only sugar.
I love sugar.
But on Lishan Mountain,
there was no sugar.
Isn't there honey to eat?
It's just not the same.
After there was no sugar,
year after year,
I missed it more and more.
Back then, I thought I wouldn't
eat meals anymore
after leaving the mountain.
For my three meals a day,
I'll just eat sugar.
Alright, enough.
Stop adding more.
Li.
Are you alright?
I mean,
since returning from Ye Mansion,
have you been alright?
Of course, I am perfectly fine.
Can this still taste good?
It's delicious. Try it.
It's good, right?
I'm so full.
Can you still fall asleep?
Yes.
Some people like to take a walk
when they overeat.
Some people like to just sleep it off.
My grandfather said this is a food coma,
just like when people drink too much
and want to sleep.
Stop.
Close your eyes.
Open your eyes.
Qingyu brought this from Ye Mansion.
I know it's something you treasured.
It was broken,
so I had a craftsman fix it.
♪The moonlight had scattered some dust♪
♪And the cracks in memory were covered♪
♪When did something chip away inside♪
♪It's flickering,
as if expectations were lost♪
♪You always love with pain♪
♪Forgetting you deserve to be loved too♪
Qingshuang.
My Lady.
♪You don't need to chase♪
♪After clouds that winds pursue♪
♪You can silently watch each sunrise♪
♪Finding happiness by your side♪
♪You don't need to chart a map♪
♪Of every bend where love winds on♪
♪Nor travel far to guide its course♪
♪To make your heart♪
♪Warm again♪
♪You really don't need to chase♪
♪No need to chase♪
♪That quiet and steady happiness♪
Where are you going?
To Jingzhao Prefecture.
Doesn't work start at the Mao hour?
It's still early.
What's wrong?
I want you to take a walk with me.
A walk?
But I'm a cripple.
I'll push you.
Alright.
What did His Highness call himself?
A cripple.
Are you crazy? So loud.
Come on.
Didn't you ask me?
I'm shocked. Her Highness is admirable.
Send it to the Prefecture.
Slow down.
When my mom left the mountain,
she was only 19.
As soon as she entered the capital,
she met my father.
At that time,
the Ye family was just ordinary,
living outside the city outskirts.
They were not rich,
with an empty shell
of a scholarly family.
My mom saw that my father was handsome,
fell in love at first sight,
and wanted to marry him.
Did your grandfather
agree to this match?
Of course, he didn't.
But he had no choice either.
So, he simply let my mom have her way.
Their marriage made a stir
in the capital back then.
I heard the late emperor gave a mansion
to the Ye family
along with a plaque
with an inscription, Family of Charity
to be hung in their house.
Red carpets lined the road,
and guards carried the bridal sedan.
Eighty boxes of dowry,
full of gold and jewels.
Even the accompanying maids
were dressed better
than the ladies
from ordinary official families.
You talk as if you saw it
with your own eyes.
It was a grand wedding, known to all.
My grandfather often said
my mom's life was too smooth.
Even heaven couldn't stand it,
so they made her suffer
by marrying my father.
My grandmother disliked her;
my uncle was domineering,
and my father was cowardly.
At first, they were afraid of Lishan.
My mom lived peacefully.
But after Lishan Mountain was closed,
their attitudes changed.
They became harsh,
even wanting to drive her to death.
You told me about this.
Your mom was seriously ill
and was cast out of the house.
Later, she died at Zhengyi Temple.
I lied to you.
My mom's death was suspicious.
I had always suspected it.
I didn't know the truth
until the day of the banquet.
My grandmother killed my mom.
Back then,
when my mom was seriously ill,
I found my father,
wanting him to see her one last time.
This act enraged my grandmother.
When I was away looking for a physician,
she murdered my mom.
So that day,
you returned to Ye Mansion for revenge.
They stole a very important item
from my mom.
I made a plan.
(I hired someone
to pretend to be a wizard.)
(I also found Ms. Wang's weakness)
(and had her help me scare my father.)
Go away.
(My father felt guilty towards my mom,)
so with just a little scare,
he lost his wits.
Have you found the item now?
I have some leads.
Do you still hate them?
Mo Xiuyao,
do you think there will be a day
when the sun doesn't shine?
The sun rises and sets
in an endless cycle.
Tomorrow is a new day.
My pinwheel spins faster than yours!
Wait a moment.
Stop blowing!
You're cheating.
I'm going to blow.
Take a look.
How much is this pinwheel?
Three wen.
Here.
♪My life is full of ups and downs♪
♪Every wound shows traces of love♪
♪I've seen all the withering plants
in this world♪
♪Until you went over the hills♪
♪To come close to me♪
♪I saw your tender yet unwavering eyes♪
♪Quietly full of joy and sorrow♪
♪When it's over, I stand in the light♪
♪In the reunion,
I comprehend the parting♪
♪With half a lifetime of separation,
I send love to the distance♪
♪As I travel through wind and frost,
I gaze at your figure♪
♪You never forget me,
and I always miss you♪
Your Highnesses.
You've returned.
I'm off.
Going home?
Send her home.
No need.
I want to walk by myself.
Well then, see you tonight.
See you tonight.
Wait.
Come and look.
Five wen for a skewer!
Want one?
This one?
Five wen.
Want one?
(Xiangqi Pavilion)
Well? Did you find out the whereabouts
of the edict?
Tell me. Who has it?
The current Dowager Consort,
Qin Zheng.
(I thought it was Marquis Muyang
who pressured the Ye family.)
(Turns out it was Qin Zheng
who took the edict.)
You're awake.
You shouldn't have come often.
What if your father finds out?
It doesn't matter.
I just like you.
And the Empress Dowager dotes on you.
I know you well.
So, what brings you here?
Look at this.
How did this happen?
Calluses from riding
and archery practice.
What does this have to do with me?
I have nothing to do.
Bored, so terribly bored.
Qin Zheng, please help me
secure a position.
With a job, I won't be bored.
The Zhechong Prefecture wants men
good at archery and horsemanship.
I've been training hard
and improved a lot.
I'm qualified to work there.
I can help you find a job,
but not in the Zhechong Prefecture.
Real fights happen there.
If anything should happen to you,
how would I explain it to your father?
Then why can Qin Cang do it?
He has campaigned in Huaixi for years.
Why compare?
Anyway, you just have to help me.
Qin Cang also just returned, right?
You are both brothers.
Why must you compete with him?
I'm not his brother.
His surname is Qin. Mine is Zhou.
You are both your father's sons,
just with different surnames.
Blood ties cannot be erased.
Since you hold your father in awe,
do you really not
acknowledge your brother?
Fine! If you don't do it,
he won't do it either.
Happy?
Qin Zheng
is sophisticated,
with a good background.
She is also decisive and ruthless.
One more thing,
I don't know why
she fully believed
the Empress Dowager was the chosen one.
So, since she entered the palace,
she's been close to the Empress Dowager.
And whatever the Empress Dowager did,
she gave her full support.
Now I somewhat doubt
if the edict is really in her hands.
Why?
That edict involves the Heiyun Cavalry
and the Empress Dowager's reputation.
Would she really keep such an item
in her possession?
Whether against Lishan
or the former Prince Ding,
it was Marquis Muyang who acted.
He is the blade
in the Empress Dowager's hand.
But why did Dowager Consort Qin
take the edict
from Ye Mansion in the end?
If she has ulterior motives,
she will surely hold onto the edict.
Guard Qin.
Young Lord.
Heading out?
Yes.
Did you just come back
from the Linjiao Courtyard?
I chatted with the Dowager Consort.
She gave me a fine horse.
It's a good horse from Cangbei.
However, I'm not fond
of riding and archery.
But you're skilled
in riding and archery.
How about I give the fine horse to you?
No, but thanks.
(Astrology)
(Astrological Divination)
Are you interested in this?
You know what?
The Dowager Consort
has quite a deep understanding
of astrology.
She says all things in the world
have their own ways.
Fathers and sons, brothers,
all have their own bonds.
If you are interested,
how about I take you
to see the Dowager Consort next time?
No need.
(Jingzhao Prefecture)
Prefect Mo.
Someone has reported
that eight years ago, Ye Wending,
along with his servant, Sun Fu,
murdered a maidservant.
The whereabouts of the remains
are unknown.
Take some men to Ye Mansion
and arrest Sun Fu.
Make him confess,
and find out where the body was buried.
Ye Mansion?
Your wife's family home.
Is there another Ye Mansion
in the capital?
That maidservant's name was Yanlu.
Her family lived
in Tulin Alley, East Ward.
Her parents are still alive,
and she has a young brother.
Back then, after Sun Fu killed her,
he lied to her family,
saying Yanlu had gone
to Lishan Mountain with her masters.
Once you find her dead body,
if verified,
send her body to her family.
- Yes.
What about the Penglai Alley case?
Here it is.
Everyone who participated that day
is on this list.
Your Highness, why do you want
to investigate these people?
After we received the news,
we immediately mustered our troops.
Jingzhao Prefecture and Penglai Alley
are three wards apart.
Once we reached Penglai Alley,
we split into two groups.
Four entrances on the front and back.
At most,
the third quarter of the Xu hour.
Our plan was flawless.
Our timing was very tight.
But just as we were about
to capture Red Fox,
someone rushed over and rescued him.
So, you suspect someone among us
leaked the information?
They ran into us.
It means they must have
just received the message.
So the leaker
is among the guards we brought along.
Go and investigate.
Find out who wasn't at the scene
when we tried to capture Red Fox,
or who left midway.
I took a rough look at this list.
They are all newcomers
without deep roots in the capital.
If someone turned traitor,
it's likely that they were bought off
with money.
Then check their recent spending.
Who has purchased property?
Who is in debt?
Investigate it clearly.
Since it is someone who can be bought,
there must be a reason
they need the money.
Yes.
Your Highness, be careful.
Don't burn yourself.
Your Highness, let me do it.
No.
Your Highness, be careful.
Your Highness.
Any movement from Jingzhao Prefecture?
They're investigating Yuan Fang's case.
Although Red Fox gave himself away,
I've sent him out of the city.
This lead is now dead for them.
You can be at ease for now.
Are we just going
to watch them tread on us?
Prince Ding is not our enemy.
Mo Xiuwen died at the hands
of Zhou Jing and the Empress Dowager.
Mo Xiuyao is bent on upending the case
of his brother and the Heiyun Cavalry.
We can work with him.
He's long since sided with the Emperor.
What does that matter?
His goal is to deal with Marquis Muyang.
The Empress Dowager
trusts Marquis Muyang.
The greater Mo Xiuyao's power grows,
the more fiercely the Emperor will fight
with the Empress Dowager.
The situation is complex and dynamic.
Things may not go exactly as you wish.
Your Highness,
you can see the situation.
Why are you bent on treating Mo Xiuyao
as a mortal enemy?
Who let you in?
I just knocked on the door.
You're injured.
I'm injured.
I accidentally fell yesterday.
His Highness was just
helping dress my wound.
I shall take my leave.
That day, I saw you go out.
You must have been mistaken.
That day, I was dead drunk
and sleeping the whole time.
How could I have gone out?
How does it feel? Does it hurt?
It doesn't hurt.
Give it a try.
You are recovering very well.
Standing up is just a matter of time.
No need to be so surprised.
I also need to see how your leg recovery
is progressing,
so I can prepare the next prescription
for you.
♪Love is not just romance♪
If you can stand,
try taking a couple of steps forward.
♪Why do two struggling souls make a vow♪
♪And stake everything♪
♪Hardship makes us sensible♪
Yes, just like that.
Take your time.
♪To live once more for each other♪
♪To become a better version
of ourselves♪
♪Love has never been just this.
Who knows♪
♪Nobody acknowledges your persistence♪
♪If the soul comes with thorns♪
♪Embrace to feel♪
♪Or the green branch offered as a tutor♪
♪Like friends
always standing side by side♪
♪Love is but a beginning,
knowing each other day and night♪
♪On such a long road,
holding hands and never letting go♪
♪Only then do we understand why love♪
♪Means more than one thing♪
Your Highness.
Are you feeling unwell?
Are you alright?
Li.
Thank you.
♪The little and big things left
in each other's lives♪
♪Along the way,
we've skipped the explanation of love♪
♪Seeing a complete life♪
♪Becoming mirrors for each other♪
♪Love has never been just this.
Who knows♪
♪Nobody acknowledges your persistence♪
♪If the soul comes with thorns♪
♪Embrace to feel♪
♪Or the green branch offered as a tutor♪
Your leg problem has been neglected
for so many years.
I mentioned it several times,
but you never let me try.
I had no choice
but to push you a little.
Thank you then.
Yao, I never meant to harm you.
(Pastries)
So many pastries.
So much money.
So much food.
Come on! Handing out money!
Quick!
Handing out money!
Your Highness.
What is going on here?
They're giving out money.
Attention, everyone!
His Highness is in a good mood
and will reward you all.
We're handing out snacks and money.
It's all of ours!
- It's all of ours!
- Come.
- Catch!
- Come on.
Catch!
It's all of ours. Line up.
It's mine.
Give me one!
I want one too!
This is tonic soup.
Starting today,
you no longer need to take medicine.
Acupuncture will change from once a day
to once every other day,
until you can walk normally.
This process will only be longer
than mending the broken leg bone,
and it must also not be taken lightly.
Two bowls of tonic soup daily,
finished before the Xu hour.
And you must eat more.
After meals, you can walk moderately
to help with healing
and restoring vitality.
Thank you, Li.
How many more times
are you going to thank me?
I'm truly very grateful to you.
I never thought I would stand again.
You healed my leg,
but I was once suspicious of you,
thinking you had ulterior motives.
And I lost my temper with you.
I promised to go
to your family home with you,
but I broke my promise.
Now I finally realize
you actually didn't believe
I could cure your leg before.
Since you didn't trust me,
why did you agree
to let me treat your leg?
You are so persistent.
Without letting you have a try,
who knows what you might do?
Like the whole bandit thing.
♪Smooth out the creases♪
♪So we can tightly fit together♪
♪Without you, there's no me♪
♪Passing by the world♪
♪Part of my broken self♪
♪Finds our places in an embrace♪
♪Fulfilling our wishes♪
♪Lovers remain calm and composed♪
♪Like you, like me♪
♪It's like a fond dream♪
Your Highness.
I heard you've lost your appetite
and not slept well at night.
I've prepared a soup to help you sleep.
Please have some, Your Highness.
Why haven't you gone to work,
Your Highness?
Today is a day off.
Why do I feel like
Your Highness is always on leave?
Jingzhao Prefecture collects case files
and handles matters, large and small.
My staff and I
often work late every night.
You think I'm not busy,
but that's only because other officials
go to banquets after work,
while I never attend banquets
and go straight home instead.
Well then, it seems I was wrong.
By the way,
regarding your mom's maidservant, Yanlu,
we found her dead body
and sent her body to her family.
This case is now being handled
by Jingzhao Prefecture.
How will they sentence Mr. Fu
and Ye Wending?
The murderer will be dead.
The accomplice will be removed
from office.
I don't work today.
Is there anything you want to do?
I can do it with you.
There's nothing I want to do.
What about things you want?
Just name it, and I'll find it for you.
Really?
There are many things I want.
Delicious foods, beautiful things,
fun things,
jewelry,
houses,
and antiques.
Okay, let's go.
Where to?
Jin, prepare the carriage.
Yes.
(Jinbao Shop)
Why did we come here?
To buy something.
No, I'm not going.
Jinbao Shop is a rival to my shop.
Jinbao Shop is always full of customers.
It's infuriating enough.
You want to buy things from that shop?
Let's go to Shubao Shop.
No.
It's owned by the same proprietor
as Jinbao Shop.
So are Qibao Shop,
Huibao Shop, and Linbao Shop.
So, we can't go to any of these shops?
If we rule those out,
only Shende Shop is left.
I can't just take you to the Shende Shop
and buy something for you
in your own shop.
In any case, I can't benefit my rival.
They won't earn a single coin from me.
I'll pay, anyway.
Pick whatever you like.
Alright then.
What would you like to buy?
We here mainly deal in gold,
silver, jade, precious stones,
porcelain, and ritual items.
Over here is the celadon
we just received this morning.
Is there anything you like?
Not that impressive.
Is there anything better?
Is this your first visit?
You might not know,
but our shop has a rule.
Well, to see the better goods,
one must buy 10,000 qian worth of goods.
But I want to see them now. Can't I?
Well...
Please wait a moment.
Are you two here
to see our shop's celadon?
Could you please rest
in the private room for a while?
I'll have our staff
make some preparations
and show you our finest celadon pieces.
Aren't your shop's rules very strict?
I heard new customers must
spend 10,000 qian to see better goods.
This is my first time here,
and I'm still allowed?
Rules are not fixed here.
Your presence here is a great honor
for our shop.
Rules don't matter then.
This way, please.
(Preview)
On January twelfth,
(Lishan Academy)
Ye Li left the mountain alone
with an imperial decree.
(She left the mountain alone)
(for the capital.)
Why can't Qingshuang do it?
Qingshuang?
What do you say, Qingshuang?
So, Her Highness is mentally sick?
You want to overturn their case?
Wait for the right time,
and heaven will help us.
♪Memories hold you back
from fulfilling your dreams♪
♪Only by moving forward
can you find reunion♪
♪Endings only mark new routes♪
♪It's all part of the scenery♪
♪To the horizon's call♪
♪Your journey hasn't started♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Both joy and grief
make the trip worthwhile♪
♪Trying to catch up
to your own lost shadow♪
♪Within the wilds, echoes thrive♪
♪Clear mind leads to a clear path♪
♪Be grateful to your losses♪
♪Make your steps weightless♪
♪Towards mountains,
chase the stars bright♪
♪Let time embrace you
and wash away the past♪
♪Put every twist behind you,
drift leisurely through time♪
♪Make headway against the wind,
let mountains bow to your pace♪
♪Rush towards a life without regret♪
♪Let your nature burst free♪
♪Unbound by form♪